小子 你这一晚上都死咬住我不放啊
you been nipping at me all night, son.
我想要知道的是
thing i got to figure is,
吞了那么多 你能全咽下去吗?
is you ready to bite the whole ass?
我胳膊肘前面的筹码都堆成山了
ain't me with a mountain by my elbow.
好吧 目前你的状态是不错了
oh, so you doing all right.
你喜欢老爷车吗?
you like the town car?
你们这些年轻人 都喜欢像雷克萨斯了
you young'uns, you all into them lexus
他妈吵得要死的VSU
and hum-fucking vsu
U-ray或是一些其他的烂车
fucking u-ray or some shit,
真搞不懂 但至于我?
i don't know. see, but me?
我还是喜欢老爷车
i like me a town car.
开那种车的人看起来沉稳正直
man look quiet and correct in one of them.
所以我跟你说
so, i tell you what--
你如果能赢这一把
you win this,
小子 你就有钱去给自己买一辆了
you be sure to pick one up for yourself, son.
再见
bye-bye.
表演时间
showtime.
妈的 黑鬼 翻牌
shit, nigger, turn.
全是梅花
man got clubs.
听好了 早晚有一天我要从这儿赢辆劳斯莱斯?
one day soon i'm walking out with a rolls, hear?
小子 就你在这儿上课的表现来看
way you been going to school up in this here room, son,
我很怀疑你能不能赢到车
i suspect you're gonna walk out of here
还让他妈的摩根·弗里曼(黑人影星)来给你开回家
with morgan-fucking-freeman to drive it for you, too.
下次见
see y'all next time.
- 嘿 - 我在Monroe附件的一家便利店
- yo. - i'm up the grocery on monroe.
好的
all right.
水 1块
water, $1.
他妈搞什么?
what the fuck?
你以为我的梦想就是他妈的
you think i dream of coming to work up
周日早上来这儿上班嘛?
in this shit on a sunday morning?
跟我朋友说我的工作有多好?
tell all my friends what a good job i got?
我工作是为了养家糊口
i'm working to support a family, man.
装的好像我不是在跟你说话一样
pretend i ain't talking to you.
装的好像我这人根本不存在一样
pretend like i ain't even on this earth.
我知道你这种人
i know what you are.
本不想找事儿 但我也是个爷们
and i ain't stepping to, but i am a man.
你偷拿东西 就好像完全不知道
and you just clip that shit
我的存在似的
and act like you don't even know i'm there.
确实不知道
i don't.
我就在这
i'm here.
听着 我跟你说了 我不是要找你麻烦
look, i told you i wasn't stepping to you.
我也没有不尊重你 小子
i ain't disrespecting you, son.
你的想法是一回事儿
you want it to be one way.
什么?
what?
你的想法是一回事儿
you want it to be one way.
- 真不知道你在-- - 你的想法是一回事儿
- man, i don't know what you're-- - you want it to be one way.
住嘴
man, stop.
别说了
stop saying that.
可惜现实却是另一回事儿
but it's the other way.
火线重案组 第四季 第4集
the.wire.s04e04
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
没有赢家 只是一方输的慢一些罢了  --Prez
我是说 天 看她那哼哼唧唧的样子  我真想
i'm saying, man, the way she was all, "aah" on chiquan, like,
真想 真想 真想说
like, like, like,
"笑啊 臭婊子 笑啊 啊?
"laugh now, stanky bitch! laugh now, huh?
你喜欢这样的?
how you like this?
小心我割了丫的奶子"
how you like i cut your titties off, huh?"
你他妈的离我远点
man, get the fuck away from me.
"小心我一刀把你砍成两半?"
"how you like i carve your pussy to your chin?"
嘿 够了 够了 够了 够了
yo, come on, come on, come on, come on.
- 什么? - 他说别惹他 就别惹他
- what? - he said leave him be, so leave him be.
- 我说说而已 - 说说而已
- i'm just saying. - you're just saying.
你也就是就会耍嘴皮
that's all you ever do, just say.
- 哥们 真不是盖的 - 不是盖的又怎样
- dude, shit was fucked up. - so it was fucked up.
她爸至少干掉过三个警察
her father killed, like, three police.
- 什么? - 没错 是真的
- what? - nah, it's true.
她爸至少干掉过三个警察  她妈会把猫煮了吃
her father killed like three police, and her mama boil cats.
- 胡说的吧 黑鬼 - 我亲耳听说的
- nigga, please, man. - it's what i heard.
她会炖猫肉 还把猫肉拿去卖
she boil cats and serve 'em and shit.
卖给谁 卖给那些会煮猫肉吃的混蛋们?
serve 'em to who, boiled-cat-eating motherfuckers?
- 谁会想要吃水煮猫肉呢 啊? - 听说她就是以此为生的
- who want him some boiled cats, huh? - heard that's how she live.
黑鬼 你丫脑子被煮了吧
nigger, you been boiled.
Laetitia在Edmondson外的教养院
laetitia live up one of them group homes off edmondson.
在他们那儿
in them places,
不用吃猫肉 人也会被逼疯的
you don't need to eat cats to make you crazy.
嘿 教练!
hey, coach!
如果那孩子不来  那你就让我跟Michael上台打一场吧
if the boy not coming, you might as well let me and michael go in the ring.
你们今天没人见过Spider吗?
ain't none of y'all seen spider today?
我没看见他
i ain't seen him.
那他下周还能不能去打了啊
now how in the hell he gonna fight next week
这一直都不来训练的?
if he don't show up to train?
这么跟你说吧
i tell you what--
在那孩子露面上课之前
until the boy shows up for his lesson,
你去把护带捆紧了 好好上场打一次
you can lace 'em up and step on the mat one time.
不 不 不 不
no no no no no.
不是他 是我
not him. me.
哦 哦 哦 哦
oh-ho-ho-ho.
我会尽量温和的告诉你
i'm gonna show you as gently as i can how much
- 你还有多少东西要学的 好吧? - 好的
- you don't know, a'ight? - a'ight.
哈哈 黑鬼 你的屁屁不保喽
yeah, nigger, that's yo ass.
要被打得屁滚尿流喽
you about to get yo ass whipped.
Sabbath：犹太教安息日周五日落至周六日落
你是Sabbath最棒的吗?
your sabbath best?
多留一会 你就能看到我是如何教育小辈儿了
you hang around, you can see me preach on some young'uns,
扎实的左勾拳 出神入化的右勾拳
solemn left and sanctified right.
执事 你怎么周日过来了?
why you down here on a sunday, deacon?
你得去Tilghman初中见见Donnelly女士
you need to see ms. donnelly at tilghman middle.
她需要人去做 你所谓的监护工作
she's got some custodial work, you might call it.
工会工资标准
union wage.
- 监护工作? - 明天去见Donnelly女士
- custodial? - see ms. donnelly tomorrow.
她解释的比我更清楚
she can explain it better than i can.
跟我说说
tell me something--
你怎么这么英明 总能知道谁该到哪儿去找谁呢?
how is it you got so much wisdom about who should be where?
一个尽职的教会执事管的就是大家的闲事
a good church man is always up in everybody's shit.
我们就是干这个的
that's how we do.
嘿 教练 准备好了吗
yo, coach, you ready?
谁赢了?
who's winning?
没有赢家 只是一方输的慢一些罢了
no one wins. one side just loses more slowly.
我们出门转转吧?
why don't we get out of the house?
散散步 今天天儿挺好的
take a walk. it's a nice day.
我要在第一节课跟学生讲讲
i got this talk i got to give to my first period...
发生了什么
about what happened.
一小时?
an hour.
我必须...
i got--
我得跟孩子说点什么
i gotta say something to those kids.
我是说
i mean--
好的
okay.
看吧 有人要赢了
see? somebody's winning.
我以为你明天才会来
i didn't expect you till tomorrow.
我听说新组有周末值班的
i heard my new squad had the weekend shift.
再说了 我想如果我能在周日
and besides, i figured if i got my shit out of
避开重大犯罪案件的话
major crimes on the sunday,
我就能避开那个丧门星Marimow了
i wouldn't have to run into that cocksucker marimow.
Marimow可是不会轻易放弃人才的
marimow does not cast off talent lightly.
他会用尽力气把人才丢的远远的
he heaves it away with great force.
Freamon周五到了
freamon got here friday.
没错Lester就是这么神速
yeah, lester's quick like that.
这是副总警监的办公室
there's the colonel's office.
这是我的陋室 公告板
this is my humble abode. the board.
这边 是你的桌子
and over here, this is your desk.
- 很干净 - 你能搞定
- it's clean. - you'll fix that.
桌子太干净说明主人脑子不正常
a clean desk is the sign of a sick mind.
凶杀组
homicide.
妈的
damn.
我不知道你的椅子哪儿去了
i don't know where your chair went.
就当是你的第一个案子吧
make that your first case.
咱能把东西放下吗? 从现在起  你就在这儿过了
and put that down, will you? you live here now.
哦 看
ooh, look.
真正的 警察工作
actual po-lice work.
- 是这些人中的一个吗? - 是他 就是他
- any of these? - he the one, right there.
他就朝着Fruit的脑袋开了一枪
just put it to fruit's head,
接下来Fruit就瘫倒在了地上
and the next thing fruit on the ground flopping,
然后他的女友就开始尖叫
and his girl all screaming,
接着你就看到粉红色的东西从他 脑袋旁边流出来
and this pink shit coming out the side of his head.
"抓狂"
"the bunk,"
忙碌的周末啊
working weekends.
投入的很呢
the man's dedicated.
我准备让你跟Crutchfield搭档开始工作
i'm gonna partner you with crutchfield to get started.
头几个月不会给你什么大案子
you won't catch anything as a primary for the first few months.
给你时间来熟悉基本情况
give you time to learn the basics.
按年分类的凶杀案档案
our h files by year.
目击证人档案存放处
witness dump.
被剪断的领带坟墓
our cut necktie mausoleum.
咖啡间...
the coffee...
信箱 根据班次和组别分类的
and the mailboxes, arranged by shift and squad.
Lester
lester.
相信你俩同病相怜的就不用再介绍了
i believe you two refugees know each other well.
还没有完全搞明白呢?
still getting your head around it?
没呢 是的
a bit, yeah.
没问题的 你没问题的
you'll do fine. just fine.
虽然这是温情时刻 但探长 有你的邮件
as tender as this moment may be, detective, you've got mail.
这么快Lyon就给你找麻烦来了?
you got lyon on your ass already?
又有人更换甲烷管道了
another switch-up on the methane probes.
要回一下那个电话
i'd call that number.
在你接到真正的案子之前先处理下这烂摊子
get on top of that shit before you catch a case,
有椅子 没椅子
chair or no chair.
甲烷管道是什么玩意?
what the hell is a methane probe?
你好 Kathleen O'Shea
hello, kathleen o'shea.
- 是的 你好? - 嗯
- yes, hello? - mm-hmm.
我要跟Lyon先生聊聊协议的事儿
i need to speak with mr. lyon about the protocols.
你说什么?
i beg your pardon?
请Lyon（狮子)先生接电话
mr. lyon, please.
亲爱的 你的声音听起来太成熟了 不适合
you sound a little old for this, hon.
说什么呢?你是谁?
excuse me? who is this?
我是Greggs警探
this is detective greggs with the--
这里是Baltimore城市公园
this is the baltimore city zoo.
好吧 我是Greggs警探
fine, and this is detective greggs--
你打电话来找 "狮子先生"
and you're calling for a "mr. lion."
抱歉
i'm sorry.
我打错了
i misdialed.
甲烷管道
methane probe.
- 刀疤Faggot - 嗯
- scarred-up faggot. - hmm.
我会穷追到底的
i need to hunt him down,
谁也保不了那畜生
'cause there ain't no protection against that shit.
没办法在Nigger那儿做手脚
can't plan against that nigger.
就好像 好像 你知道他像什么的
it's like, like, you know what he's like.
他像什么?
what he like?
他就像那些天杀的恐怖分子一样
he like one of them terrorist motherfuckers.
看谁不爽就炸谁
just blowing up shit just to.
根本不在乎谁会受伤 有没有意义
don't care who get hurt, what kind of sense it makes.
说得有理啊
he got a point.
说到政府
and the government, right?
如果有恐怖袭击
if they have one of them terrorist attacks,
他们就会去帮Delta或是其他什么人的忙
they cut delta or whoever some slack.
保险公司 银行
the insurance companies, the banks,
还有他妈的什么纳斯达克 就有足够的时间把自己欠下的债还了
the whole nasdaq and shit get some time to pay back what they owe,
因为政府知道自己什么都做不了
because the government know ain't nothing they could do.
哈
huh.
没错 我知道你明白 你看的是大局
yeah, i know you see it. you see the big picture.
但今天说道黑鬼的问题 他们只会睁只眼闭只眼
problem with niggers today, they always see the narrow view.
- 那个不错 - 什么?
- that's nice. - what?
哦 你喜欢?
oh, you like that?
我带了有好久了
i had it for a long time now.
都带出感情了
it's got some sentimental values.
- 不过是个东西 - 值多少钱?
- just a thing. - what's the real value?
- 啊? - 值多少钱?
-Huh?  -Real value?
感情对我来说没什么意义
i ain't much for sentiment.
哦 你知道的
oh, you know.
有段时间没有查过了
it's been a while since i checked.
我是说 全球经济起起伏伏的
i mean, the fluctuation in the global economy and all.
- 我会帮你查的 - 不用麻烦你的
- i'll find out for you. - you don't have to.
我会帮你查的
i'll find out for you.
这些年指头都变粗了
finger's swelled over the years.
- 要帮忙吗? - 没错 嘿 要帮忙吗?
- need some help? - yeah, man, you need help?
不用 不用
i got it, i got it.
- 用点唾沫润滑 - 我可不想碰他的唾液
- maybe use some spit. - i don't want the man's spit.
不用 我取下来了
no, i got it now.
Omar不是什么恐怖主义者
omar ain't no terrorist.
他不过是另一个拿着枪的黑鬼
he just another nigger with a gun.
你也不是什么Delta航空公司的
and you ain't no delta airlines, neither.
你只是个被抢了东西的黑鬼
you just a nigger got your shit took.
所以 把你欠的债还了
so, bring me what you owe
去他妈别处跟人扯全球经济
and talk that global economy mess somewhere else.
明白了
feel me?
嗯
yeah.
我又牵了个局
i got another game.
你已经输了多少了?
how much you down already?
有耐心才能学会他们的方式
learning their ways requires some patience.
也需要点钱
some money, too.
这次你要多少?
how much you need this time out?
一百五差不多了
a hundred and a half ought to do.
一百五?
a hundred and a half?
很快我就能搞定那白痴了
i take that chicken-nose fool one day soon.
也会除掉那个肉中刺
take super stick, too.
除掉所有人
take 'em all.
也许我玩腻了 就让你去干掉他们
else, maybe i get bored, send you to take 'em.
我是说 Foerster副总警监
and my point, colonel foerster,
你的人Norris
is that your man norris,
我听说 他天天无所事事
he's fucking the dog on this, way i hear it.
长官 当务之急要处理的是这个案子
sir, this is a top priority case,
Norris知道 有人想谋杀目击证人
and norris knows there's a possibility of a murdered state's witness.
我们现在还不确定那是否就是杀人动机呢
we don't even know yet if that was the motive for the murder.
- 这才是我的重点 - Norris很专业 长官
- this is my point. - norris is a pro, sir.
可他今年的破案率 显得他很业余
his clearance rate this year says otherwise, colonel.
长官 Norris是个好警察
sir, norris is good police.
听着Ray 我们需要的是能勤奋工作的人
look ray, we need someone who can work it hard,
能24小时连轴转 不到累趴下 不停工的人
work it around the clock, work it till it falls.
我理解凶杀重案组有新鲜血液进来
and i understand we just pumped some fresh blood into homicide--
女警 上次进来女警已经是几年之前了
female, took one in the line a few years back.
她没有处理过凶杀案
she's never worked homicide.
那就是新人新眼光了
fresh eyes, then.
长官 我不想冒犯您
but with all due respect, sir,
如果我能够保证这个案子相关的信息
if i could guarantee that no further information
在选举进行之前
on this case would be leaked to the press,
不在媒体面前走漏半点风声
certainly not before election day,
你能让经验丰富的老兵去调查吗 长官?
would it be possible to keep veteran investigators working it, sir?
这样含沙射影的 真是惹人厌
i resent the implication.
我很抱歉 长官
my apologies, sir.
你来这儿纯属浪费我的时间
you killing my time coming up here.
而且 也许你还是不明白 这也是在浪费钱
and if you ain't noticed, it's costing us money.
如果你继续满嘴谎话 要我怎么相信你
how am i gonna trust you if you keep telling lies,
说一样做的却是另一样?
saying one thing and doing another?
我只有周五没去 仅此而已
i just missed friday, that's all.
听着 这么说吧
look, think on it like this--
上学跟工作是一样的 现在他们是一样的
school is work. they're the same thing right now.
所以 你逃学就跟你翘班结果是一样的
so, you skipping out on school is like not showing up for work.
我听够了 受够了 也不想再继续拆穿那些借口了
and i done heard, made up, and tested every excuse invented.
所以 除非你死了 或是快死了 别的什么理由又没用
so, unless you dead or dying, there ain't none you can use.
跟你说了 我会去
i told you i'm-a go.
好的 好吧 我知道了
yeah, okay, i know.
为了学习 为了离开这一行 你也必须要去
for school or out the business, you are gonna go.
快来
come on.
新学期一开学就拉了这么多课可不好
falling behind now isn't the way to start out a school year,
尤其是你已经有三年没上学了
particularly after a three-year hiatus.
自从你注册之后 我们就没见过你
we haven't seen you since you enrolled.
有什么原因才没来的吗?
is there a reason you haven't joined us?
听着 我知道您曾经想帮Sherrod
look, i know you reaching out for sherrod.
我替这孩子向您道歉
i want to apologize for the boy
因为他一直在努力工作 帮我经营小本生意
because he's been working hard at helping me get a business going.
但是他得回到这儿来
but he need to be here though.
这是毫无疑问的
ain't no bout a-doubt it.
一切都是他说了算 不是吗?
it's up to him, isn't it?
这正是我一直想说的 他就是来说这个的
that's what i've been trying to say. that's it right there.
你怎么说呢 年轻人?
what about it, young man?
我没问题
i'm good.
好的
okay.
还有一件困扰我的事情 女士
one thing though been bothering me, ma'am--
Sherrod已经辍学三年了
if sherrod already missed the last three years,
那他是不是该重新念五年级或是六年级呢
should he maybe be back in the fifth or sixth grade,
能不根据他的年龄决定吗 我是说 这样他才能跟上
instead of up with his age: i mean, so he can follow the work.
自动升级
social promotion.
不好意思
excuse me:
我们现在没有足够的资源能让他复读的
we don't have the resources to repeat grade levels,
再说 我们也觉得把年长的孩子放到 低年级的班里
and we feel to place the older children in the younger classes
对于需要维持课堂秩序的老师来说很不公平
is unfair to teachers who are responsible for maintaining order.
你的侄子会自动升级
your nephew has been socially promoted.
他是八年级生了 马上就要升入高中了
he's an eighth-grader, headed to high school.
抱歉但是Johnson女士来谈Qadriyyah的事儿
sorry, but ms. johnson's here about qadriyyah.
失陪一下
excuse me for a moment.
- Bill 这真是不可理喻 - 我跟他说了
- bill, this is nuts. - i told him that.
知道吗 一旦消息外漏 你觉得谁会倒霉?
you know if this gets out, who do you think it's gonna land on?
我还有两年时间去赚4万块 还有我的养老金
i got two years to make 40 and a pension bump.
听着 我也不赞同这个决定
look, i don't agree with the call either,
但这是他的决定 不是你的 也不是我的
but it's his call, not yours, not mine.
反正每天到市政厅挨训的那个人是他
he's the one over at city hall every day getting his ass chewed.
我才不在乎你说什么呢 天 你开的头
i don't care about nothing you say, man, 'cause if you start shit,
你就没资格管别人怎么收尾的
you can't complain how somebody finish that shit.
老天 她从一开始就注意她了
man, she was on her from the beginning
留意那小镜子及所有的细节 天 我也不会等的
with the mirror and everything, man. i wouldn't have waited.
Pryzbylewski老师 这就是Sherrod
mr. pryzbylewski, this is sherrod.
- 交给你了 - 好的
- and he's all yours. - okay.
去坐吧 Sherrod
take a seat, sherrod.
好的 听我说
okay, listen up.
我要... 大家...
i'd like to-- everybody--
所有人安静 我想聊聊...
everybody, i'd like to talk--
听我说!
listen up!
现在 我们都知道
now, we all know something, um,
上周五在这儿发生了件很不愉快的事儿
unpleasant happened here friday,
还有 听着 我知道你们还在试图搞清楚...
and, look, i know some of you are still trying to get your heads around--
又不是我的脑袋被开瓢了
ain't my head got a big old gash.
- 并且 呃 我也希望跟你们讨论一下 - 那个 你真的是警察吗?
and, uh, l'd like to discuss-- - yo, is it true that you police?
什么?
what?
Carmandy小姐亲口在办公室说 "Prezbo老师是个警察"
miss carmandy up in the office say, "mr. prezbo, he police."
- 喂 你是警察 啊? - 开枪打过人吗?
- yo, you police, man? - you ever shoot somebody?
- 我想我们还是应该谈谈 - 他才不会开枪打人呢
- i think we should talk about-- - he ain't shot no one.
看看他
look at him. yo,
你有没有抓过一个叫Ashanti Graham的人?
you ever bust a man named ashanti graham?
有时候 当一些不好的事情发生时
sometimes when something bad happens--
- 是你爸? - 不 是我哥
- that your dad? - nah, my brother.
为什么你不能告诉我们 你有没有开枪打过人?
why can't you tell us if you shot somebody or not?
- 你用得是什么枪? - 你是缉毒刑警吗?
- what kind of gun you carry? - you narco?
我曾经做过警察
i used to be police.
但我现在是老师
now i'm a teacher.
做警察可不只是配把枪那么简单
but being a police isn't just about carrying a gun.
是的 没错
yeah, right.
警察是为社区工作的
it's about working with the community.
社区?你们可没来过我们社区
the community? y'all ain't been up in my community
好久没见过你们了 除了偶尔见你们来羞辱人
in a long time except to whale on people.
嘿 P老师 你中过枪吗 我是说 像这样 嘣
yo, mr. p, you ever been shot? i mean, like, bah.
Namond
namond
够了
that's enough.
起来
get up.
起来 回到座位上去 谢谢 很有趣
get up. get back in your seats. thank you, very entertaining.
坐下 会你们的位子上去
sit down. get in your seats!
坐下 坐下 Kwaneese 坐下
sit down, sit down. kwaneese, sit down.
都坐好了
sit down, now.
嗨 P老师 你有没有这么勒死过人啊?
yo, mr. p, you ever choke somebody dead like--
嘿 你被别人拍过吗?
yo, you ever get videoed?
P老师 Ashanti Graham
mr. p, ashanti graham.
你肯定听说过他 他可是个货真价实的浑蛋
you gots to know him. he was a player for real.
他在这儿工作 周日到周四
he work sunday to thursday,
朝七晚五
7:00 early to 5:00 late.
那就是说 他不用值夜班了
so, it ain't no moonlighting thing, then.
不用 他不是真正的警察
nah, he ain't no real police.
不过是在这儿做个全职的米老鼠 当摆设罢了
he full-time on this mickey mouse shit here.
那他到底是干嘛的?
what he do again?
顶嘴
talked back.
要去Hilltop转一圈?
go over hilltop now?
没错 也是我们的地盘了
yeah, we got that, too.
回见
see ya.
该下决定了 小子
decision time, son.
嘿 你到底想怎样?
yo, what's your play?
好吧 我跟就那边的小Kevin说过两次 要打爆你俩的脑袋
well, i told little kevin right there to shoot y'all both in the head twice.
不过现在已经吓不跑他了...
but seeing as he done walked away...
哦 你真幽默
oh, you funny.
那是 我想 我还是跟你们混了
yeah, i guess i'm on your package.
那个叫Michael的孩子在哪儿?
where the boy at-- michael?
那个 他不是正式入行  不过是为了还债做了一阵子
well, he ain't no regular. he's just working off a debt.
- 怎么了? 你怎么问起他了? - 别再"怎么了"
- why? why you care? - never mind you why.
"怎么了"已经不再是你能管的了 黑鬼
"why" ain't in your repertoire no more, nigger.
六四开
60-40 split on that.
Marlo的钱 你可别想玩花样
do not be messing with marlo's money.
Randy Wagstaff
randy wagstaff,
你不是六年级生 对吧?
you aren't a sixth-grader, are you?
喔 嘿 Reese女士
uh, hey, ms. reese.
如果你是六年级生
if you were a sixth-grader,
那你跟其他那些蠢蛋们
it would mean you and the rest of the knuckleheads
就该在我的教室上第一节的英语课呢
would still be in my first-period english class.
那也就意味着这事儿应该发生在两年前
and that would mean it was two years ago.
那也就意味着Tilghman初中的时间停滞了
and that would mean time stands still at tilghman middle,
那可就真的坏事儿了
and that would be a catastrophe.
我只是忘记了 今天又穿了我的旧衬衣
i just forgot and wore my old shirt today.
好吧 如果这不是你的午饭 那你的通行条在哪儿?
well, if this isn't your lunch, then where is your hall pass?
你干吗不干脆用蜡笔写呢?
why not just write it in crayon?
走吧
come on.
Deacon说你是个好人
deacon says you're a good man.
我想 也就仅限于能挥挥拖把
good enough to swing a mop, i guess.
拖把? 应该说更像是吸尘器
a mop? more like a vacuum cleaner.
什么?
what?
每年九月都会有一群 像你一样的小伙子们会来帮我
i get a few fellas like you to help me out every september.
你们到外面去
you go out on the street,
找到这些孩子 带他们回来
you find these kids, you drag them in.
哦 逃学督察员
oh, a truant officer.
系统已经有20年没有拨款给逃学督察员了
the system hasn't been funded for truant officers in 20 years.
Montgomery郡：在华盛顿附近 是美国最富裕的郡之一
你以为你在哪儿Montgomery郡?
where the hell you think you are, montgomery county?
甭想了 我每年会预留几个监护工作岗位
nah, i keep a couple custodial positions
就是为了这个
unfilled every year just for this.
那些孩子?你把他们拽回来 然后把他们名字从名单上划掉
those kids? you haul 'em in, you cross 'em off the list.
每个孩子 带回来一次 清了名单
each kid, one time, clear the list.
10月再来 再重新按名单清理一遍
come october, you start on the list again.
如果你想要 这份工作就是你的了 每小时12块
job's yours if you want it. pays $12 an hour.
失陪一下 亲爱的 去坐下
excuse me, hon. sit.
为什么要逃课?
why'd you leave class?
我饿了 没法集中精力
i got hungry, couldn't concentrate.
也许 Randy 你还有别的原因在走廊游荡 嗯?
maybe, randy, you had another reason for running the halls, huh?
也行 又要去墙上涂鸦?
tagging walls, maybe?
你知道我没弄
uh-uh. you know i don't.
我什么都不知道 我只知道这才第二周
i don't know anything. i know it's the second week,
我的墙上已经画满了涂鸦
and i got walls covered with tags.
从那涂鸦旁边走过 感觉不错吧?
does that make you feel good,
- 我不知道 - 也许 你不知道
- i don't know. - maybe you don't know,
因为就是你画的
'cause you're the one doing the marking.
- 我没有 - 那是谁?
- i'm not. - then who is
- Thompson女士? - 嗯 女士?
- miss thompson? - yes, ma'am?
麻烦你帮我拿一下 Randy Wagstaff养母的电话?
could you get me the number for randy wagstaff's foster mom?
- 没问题 - 打电话给Anna女士干嘛?
- not a problem. - what you want to call miss anna for?
因为你逃课 在学校走廊游荡
because you're skipping class, running the halls,
也许还有更恶劣的行为 她有权知道
maybe worse. she's got a right to know.
- 这是她的办公电话? - 是的 女士
- is this her work number? - yes, ma'am.
等一下 等等
hold on. wait.
新来的女生 Greggs--
the new girl, greggs--
长官 无意冒犯 不过
sir, if i may, respectfully--
Norris已经忙得不可开交了
norris has a full plate, okay?
Braddock的案子交给Greggs了
the braddock case goes to greggs.
他没那么忙
his plate is fine.
才没 他很忙  他手头有一堆的活儿 行吗?
no, it's not. his plate's a pile of shit, okay?
听我说
listen to me.
Burrell希望在大家投票之前 先缓缓查这案子
burrell wants this case stalled until everybody votes.
那Rawls呢?
and rawls?
我他妈的怎么会知道Rawls要什么呢?
how the fuck i know what rawls wants?
他连屁都不放一个
he never said shit.
这么跟你说吧 就算他知道这事儿搞砸了 他也不会吱声的
and let me tell you something, even he knows this is fucked up.
以防我弄错了
i have this correct,
我们把有经验的老手从悬而未决的案子 中撤出了 而换个新人接手案子
we are pulling a veteran off a pending case and giving it to a rook
就是为了让刚提到的案子?
so as not to make timely progress on said case?
把Braddock的案子给Greggs
the braddock case to greggs.
- 一个实验项目? - 在你们其中一所初中设立 没错
- a pilot program? - for one of your middle schools, yes.
- 还有附带的20万 - 额外的费用
- a $200,000 grant is attached. - free money.
- 我只是想帮忙 Conway女士 - 怎么帮?
- i'm just trying to help, mrs. conway. - help how?
你说你们的受众是
you say that your target group is
多次出现暴力倾向的人
repeat violent offenders.
不管怎样 你不是暗示说我们的系统 已经管不了那学校了吧?
are you in any way suggesting that the system's lost control of the school?
不 不 不 我一点也没有那个意思
no no no, that's not what i'm suggesting at all.
系统没问题 系统很不错的
the system's fine. the system's great.
我是说 这跟系统没什么关系
i mean, this isn't about the system.
我们只是希望能找到一种方法能够帮助
we're just gonna try to find a way to get to some of the troubled kids
那些即将脱离系统的问题孩子
who won't be in the system too much longer.
好吧 听着 只要你能保证不会惹麻烦
well, look, just make sure there's no fuss.
我是说 我不希望有任何人为此不开心  知道吗?
i mean, nothing that gets anyone upset, you know?
大选在即 我们不希望我们的学校
there's an election going on, and we don't want to put our schools
惹上任何麻烦
in the middle of that mess.
不 真的不会
no, indeed.
拉着警笛跑 很拉风啊
humping a radio car like a young sprite.
认识你我都有点自豪了 Mcnulty长官
i'm a little bit proud to know you, officer mcnulty.
只是有点儿吗?
just a little bit?
好吧 就好像除了拉警笛之外  你就没有更拉风的事儿做一样
well, it ain't like there aren't better things you could be doing.
- 比如呢? - 看吧 早跟你说了 Lester
- like what? - see, i told you, lester,
我的孩子已经不再做病猫 开始发威了
the worm has turned for my boy.
那个 我听说他们彻底毁了你的窃听装置
so, i heard they torpedoed your wiretap.
没错 他们给我们派了个新警官
yeah, they sent us a new lieutenant.
- 来自E&T的Marimow - "团队杀手"
- marimow from e&t. - "the unit killer."
Lester和Kima已经脱身转到了凶杀案组
lester and kima already bailed to homicide,
而且现在Sydnor能找到好的职位也会跳走的
and now sydnor's looking to jump at the first good opening.
那么 重案组就是死了啊?
so, major crimes is dead, huh?
- 没错 Lester成功把它干掉了 - 去找钱了
- yeah, lester killed it good. - went looking for the money.
像你这样的就是撞到南墙也不回头啊
guys like you, you never learn.
- 像我这样的? - 是啊 13年--
- guys like me? - yeah, 13 years--
- 四个月 - 四个月
- four months. - four months.
你们是在叫后援啊 还是怎么?
you guys call for backup or what?
嗯
yeah.
我们拿到了杀人犯Curtis Anderson 别名"Lex"的逮捕令
we got arrest papers on a murder for one curtis anderson, aka "lex."
他在这几周都在这一区活动
he's been on the wing for a couple of weeks,
虽说不期望能在他妈妈家逮到他 不过也说不准
so i don't expect him at his mama's, but you never know.
- 地址? - 643 Harlem
- what's the address? - 643 harlem.
看在以前的情面上 跟我一起去如何 Jim?
how about you taking the door with me for old time's sake, jim?
- 我帮你抄后门 先生们 - 哦!
- i'll take the back, gents. - oh!
后门? 妈的 孩子 你确实不做病猫要发威了
the back? damn, junior, the worm has turned for you.
你知道他们怎么形容自愿守后门的人吗?
you know what they say about the man who volunteers to take the back?
他会买单
he buys.
B&O酒馆 今晚9:00 孩子
b&o tavern, tonight at 9:00, son.
- 1点之后 我就不进那地方了 - 妈的
- i throw myself out after one. - shit.
不信我 那你可以问Bunk
you don't believe me, ask bunk.
确实不假
true.
卧室安全
the bedroom's clear.
是的 地下室也一样
yeah, basement, too.
安全
clear.
好的
yeah.
安全
clear.
今晚9:00 Mcnulty
9:00 tonight, mcnulty,
B&O酒馆
b&o tavern.
跟你说过了 他不在这儿
he's not here. i told you.
他还会回家吗?
is he coming home again?
女士 你的儿子还活着吗?
ma'am, is your son alive?
如果他不在了
because if he's not,
我们立马就可以结案了
we can end this right now.
否则 我们已经找到了一名目击证人
otherwise, we've got a witness.
这样我们就能拿到凶手搜查令
that gives us a murder warrant,
根据该搜查令 如果有必要的话
and that warrant says that we can come through your door
我们随时都能来登门拜访
as many times as necessary.
我不知道我儿子在哪儿
i don't know where my son is.
就像是你养的鸟一样
it's like them birds of yours.
他们出去 自由的在这个城市飞翔
they go out, and they fly around the city.
他们想做什么就做什么
they free to do as they do.
天黑之前 他们就会回到这里
end of the day, they come back here,
找水 找食物
get water, get fed,
因为他们知道你在这 给他们留了个遮风挡雨的地儿
'cause they know you got this place set up regular as the rain.
没有意外 因为到了最后
no surprises, 'cause at the end of the day,
没人喜欢意外
a man don't want no surprises.
你知道的 鸟也不喜欢
you know, birds neither.
我给你提供的也是一样
same as what i'm offering.
如果你是组织的一员
you part of a co-op,
你再也不用为那些意外担心
a whole lot of surprises you never worry about again.
想做什么就做什么
you just do as you do,
你需要的东西永远都是准备好的
knowing the product will always be there
而且都是上乘货色
and be the finest quality;
如果条子找你们的麻烦
knowing that if one of yours takes a pinch,
在你下警车之前
he got a lawyer and a bondsman
你的律师和担保人就已经在等你了
waiting for him before he even step out the wagon.
我知道怎么请律师
i know how to hire lawyers.
请到律师是小事
it ain't just about the lawyers.
建立关系 在出事之前获取信息才是大事
it's having a connection so that you know before the bust even go down.
要得到这好处 我需要放弃什么?
what i got to give up to get that good dope?
出力就好 你能打
muscle. you got muscle.
和我们一起 把那些纽约的小子们
you stand with us, we run these new york boys
- 赶出东巴尔的摩 - 他妈的 我才不在乎东巴尔的摩
- right out of east baltimore. - fuck i care about east baltimore:
合作的重点在于 我们今后站一边了
the point of the co-op is we stand together.
我们共享资源
we share information,
没人敢惹我们
and no one fucks with any of us.
就算现在也没人敢惹我
no one fucks with me now.
好吧 但说不准今后会出现一些意料之外的情...
well, that don't mean there couldn't be some unforeseen cir--
就算现在也没人敢惹我
no one fucks with me now.
非洲色调 够狡猾的
african colors. subtle.
Tony Gray现在已经拿到了24%的选票
tony gray is pulling 24% now.
你需要一些新的色彩 传递新的信息Clarence
you need new colors and a new message, clarence.
你必须集合起来选区的所有力量
you need to rally the base.
dashiki：黑人常穿的花里胡哨的短袖套衫
你又想我穿花衬衫?
you want me to start wearing dashikis?
整的好像Marion Barry似的? (黑人 曾任华盛顿 D.C的市长)
go all marion barry and shit?
跟你说 我想要什么吧
i'll tell you what i would like--
再给我75竞选资金 现金
another 75 in cash for walk-around money.
75 呵?
75, huh?
再去设个局
call another game.
完全是浪费时间
it's a waste of time,
而现在 时间才是最宝贵的
and right now, time is everything.
他们不会给你好脸色看的  他们只会支持Royce
they're gonna spit in your eye and endorse royce.
他们等了这么久 不过是给Tony Gray几分面子
they only waited this long out of respect to tony gray.
否则一个月前他们就投票给Royce了
otherwise, they give it to royce months ago.
- 那个不是重点 - 你不请自到
- that's not the point. - you go there uninvited,
只会惹怒他们
and you're only gonna piss them off.
我会吗?
am l?
还是说我假装他们并不存在  我根本不需要他们
or do i piss them off even more by pretending that they don't exist,
会让他们更生气?
that i don't need them?
在这个城市 我挨家挨户登门拜访
i've door-to-doored every neighborhood in this city,
告诉他们 我准备好了做他们的市长
saying i'm ready to be mayor to all of it,
不仅仅是我的选区 而且全市
not just my base, but all of it.
如果我都不去见见这些人  那又怎么说的过去呢?
what does it say i don't go see these guys?
他说的没错
he's right.
他们投票给Royce也就算了 最差也不过如此了?
they endorse royce, fine. the hell else they gonna do?
不管怎样  他们周日那天在党内初选演讲台上
but what they say and don't say from the pulpit
说了的跟没说出口的话  证明我们还有胜算
that sunday before the primary, we still got a dog in that fight.
我要是办好了这事儿 就能赢得他们的尊重
i do this right, they'll respect it.
就算是不成功 至少也能让他们
and if they don't, at least they get to see a
看看一个摇尾乞怜的白人
begging-ass white man on his knees.
对他们来说 那感觉还是很不错的
always a feel-good moment for the folks.
那么 既然我参与了市政理事会 那我就说说
and as to my attendance at council meetings,
了解这份工作的人就该明白
those who know the job understand
作为市政官员 要做的
there is more to being a councilperson
绝不仅仅是开会
than just the meetings.
问吧 Charles
yes, charles?
嗯 他们在我住的街区末尾建了一间收容所 住的都是些瘾君子什么的
yeah, they putting a halfway house at the end of my block. addicts and such.
抱歉多嘴问一句
not if i have anything to say about it.
- 您在哪儿住呢 先生? - 800街 北Carrollton
- where you living at, sir? - 800 block north carrollton.
哦 我会查查看的
oh, i'm gonna take a look into that.
对于我们其他候选人 大家还有什么问题吗?
is there anyone with a question for any of the other candidates?
有意见 有疑虑吗?
anyone with an issue, a concern?
嗯 我想说 关于
well, i would say that with regard to
这位先生对于收容所的担心
the gentleman's concern about the halfway house,
虽然我与您有着同样的担心
that while i share your concern,
但这座城市里有上千名正在戒毒的瘾君子 这是事实
it's also true that the city has thousands of drug addicts in recovery,
总要为他们建一些收容所和避难处的
and those halfway houses and shelters have to go someplace.
可是就不会建在白人社区
though not in white neighborhoods.
女士 能借我看一下
ma'am, could i see that,
- Royce的宣传页吗?谢谢 - 嗯 这话说的不错
- that royce flyer? thank you. - well, that is a fair point as well.
但他们也是人
but these are people--
都是我们的兄弟姐妹
??? our brothers and sisters,
我们的孩子 我们的朋友
our children, our friends.
而且他们也在试图改变自己的命运
and they are trying to change their lives,
所以我们都有责任伸手帮他们一把
and so it's up to us to be responsible for them.
错过一圈感觉不错 啊?
feel good to miss a hand, huh?
又能怎样呢?最终我们还是会被通吃的
- what's the point? - eventually, we all got to ante up.
没错 肯定会
yeah, we do.
不过 我还真不敢相信 他这么带种
but i can't believe he had the balls enough
敢在一个月里攒两场赌局 我是说 拜托
to call two games in one month. i mean, please.
他这是在筹备竞选资金呢
he's loading up on walk-around money.
他这是在大选之前筹集现金去拉票呢
he wants cash on the street come election day.
都是受Carcetti的影响
carcetti got to him.
都能叫战争基金了
called it a war chest.
也许我们这次是要被卷入战争了
maybe we got us a war this time.
如果他没那么无耻 我也就罢了
i wouldn't mind if he wasn't so fucking ugly with it.
他看着Roger的三个九  还拿自己的一个对子赌那么大
that two pair he bet on, right into roger's trip nines.
我的同花都扣了
i folded on a flush.
(三张同号牌加一对同号牌 比同花还大)
四盘之前 我扣了葫芦
full boat, four hands ago.
这简直就是道德沦丧啊
it's immoral, what it is.
那个 这局怎样了 先生们?
so, what's the game, gents?
Clarence发牌
clarence's deal.
德州全胜
texas hold 'em.
我开始明白这游戏有多流行了
i begin to understand the popularity of this game.
完全没有限制
no limit.
哦 好牌啊
oh, peachy.
我开始觉得 你越来越不敏锐了 小子
i was beginning to think you'd lost it, son.
客厅里 她的神龛
that living room shrine of hers
会让猫王跟Tupac（歌手)两个人汗颜的
would have shamed elvis and tupac both.
她儿子活着的可能性比那两人小得多 她只是不敢承认罢了
her son's deader than both of 'em. she's just too scared to say so.
我第一次跟她谈的时候  那玩意根本就不在那
that shit wasn't there the first time i talked to her.
- 要在我肯定能看到 - 嗯 嗯
- i'd have seen it. - hmm.
- 你也算是个警探 - 嗯 嗯
- you being a detective and all. - mmm-hmm.
嘿 看 她有朋友来了
hey, look, she got a friend.
她对你来说太年轻了 孩子
she too young for you, boy.
年轻?
young?
她们更年轻了 William 也更苗条了 我们可没
they get younger, william. skinnier, too. we don't.
更年轻 更苗条 Jimmy在哪儿?
younger, skinnier-- where's jimmy?
那才是自然 年龄就是年龄
that's just the nature of things. age is age,
胖就是胖 自然就是自然
fat is fat, and nature is nature.
哦 真可悲
aw, pitiful.
不 是无情 自然才不会在乎
and pitiless. nature don't care.
那才是自然
nature just is.
说回我要找的Marlo 我觉得他是在扰乱
now my boy marlo, i thought he was skewing that.
搞砸什么?
screwing what?
- 那孩子可是头小狮子 - "你好 Lyon（狮子)先生在吗?"
- the boy's a young lion. - "hello, is mr. lyon home?"
是狮子就会猎杀动物
and a lion has to have his kill.
"甲烷管道的事儿 找一下Lyon先生"
"methane probe for mr. lyon."
- 那么我要找的尸体哪儿去了? - 嗯
- so then where are my bodies? - hmm.
现在我这边过了六个月 都找不到尸体
here i am over here on the one hand without a body in six months,
而你这边要找的嫌疑人
and here you are looking for a suspect
很可能也已经被干掉了
who's most likely dead,
很可能就是因为干掉Marlo的人 才被灭口的
and most likely for dropping one of marlo's.
话说回来 如果他死了
then again, if he's dead,
那尸体在哪儿?
where's that body?
你知道小猫咪的复数是什么吗? (小猫咪=女性生殖器)
you know what the plural of pussy is?
是喵咪 Jimmy教我的
puss-i. jimmy taught me that.
他到底把尸体藏哪儿了 Bunk 啊?
where's he putting the bodies, bunk, huh?
丢下水管道了
in the sewers:
也许在流氓葬礼之家?
rogue funeral home, maybe?
没错 他们确实天主教会学校教那些衣冠禽兽 们拉丁语 确实有教
yeah, they teach that fancy-ass latin at them catholic schools, they do.
- 你还记得Eddy Crane的案子吗? - 嗯
- you remember the eddy crane case? - mmm-hmm.
听说他们把他放进一只装满强酸的 桶里丢进了Curtis湾
word was they put him in an acid vat down near curtis bay.
她们朝我们这边走过来了
they're coming up on us now.
现在 像Marlo Stanfield这样来自西边的孩子
now, for a west side boy like marlo stanfield,
那才是传统的弃尸地点啊
that would be the traditional dumping grounds,
- 嘿 女士们 你们好啊? - 对吧?
- hey, girl. how are your doing? - right?
- 嘿 女士们 - 对吧?
- hey, girl. - right?
什么?
what?
哦 老天
oh, man.
Jimmy
jimmy.
还是找人去喵个咪啊
tying to get some of that puss-i.
他妈的 你还坐在这儿干嘛?
what the hell you still sitting here for?
他妈的 伪中产黑鬼
fucking huxtables and shit, right?
他们来了 就在那儿
there they go right there.
他还在上学
he's still with school.
妈的 每天也就是开着那破玩意儿去
shit. just so they can spring out that shit pile every day.
好好教训他一顿
make a good run at that boy,
他会乖乖帮我们运毒品的 没问题的
he'll be on a corner, no problem, man.
是啊 走着瞧
yeah, we gonna see.
你这是宿醉吧?
you hung-over?
你看起来真是糟透了
just saying you look like shit.
知道在案发现场你要带什么吗?
you know what you need at a crime scene?
- 橡胶手套 - 柔软的眼睛
- rubber gloves. - soft eyes.
妈的 我来是要大哭一场吗?
like i'm supposed to cry and shit?
如果你有柔软的眼睛 你就能眼观全局
you got soft eyes, you can see the whole thing.
如果你的眼神太过僵硬
you got hard eyes,
你看到永远都是那一棵树 而不是整片森林
you're staring at the same tree, missing the forest.
哦 参禅呢
oh, zen shit.
柔软的眼睛 蚱蜢
soft eyes, grasshopper.
看这尸体颜色 死亡时间就写7:48
lividity puts the time of death at 7:48,
- 左右 - 明白
- give or take. - noted.
到时候弄个恒化器测测
you're gonna want to get a chemstat.
- 你觉得呢? - 无所谓
- you think? - couldn't hurt.
也叫一下伤亡净化中心? 血液溅到的范围内?
a cdc, too? splatter distance?
好的 没问题
yeah, definitely.
妈的 我的棉签哪儿去了?
you know, where the hell did my q-tips go?
别担心 我的就在这儿
don't sweat it. i got mine right here.
哦 好的 没事 你要看一眼吗? 不咬人的
oh, good. it's cool. you want to take a look? won't bite.
嘿 别忘了点刻法 (骨骼-肌肉-表皮-细节)
hey, uh, don't forget the, uh, stippling.
我是新人
i'm a rookie?
- 他手里握有东西 - 哦 是吗?
- there's something in his hand. - oh, yeah?
给她把镊子
give her some tweezers.
"Tater杀了我"
"tater killed me."
哦 是打印的吗?
oh, is it typed?
是的话 到了法庭就更有说服力了
'cause that would hold up a lot better in court.
另外一只手里握着电话号码呢
phone number in the other hand.
标准的保密协议
a standard confidentiality agreement.
那这份呢?
and this one?
哦 那一份是 当你或是你的员工受伤时
oh, that one indemnifies us
我们不用负任何责任
should you or any of your staff be injured.
- 今天谁想去学点东西呢? - 这边 快走
- who wants to get some learning today? - this way. move.
- 我跟你做前排怎样? - 你的位子在后面 年轻人 走了
- i roll up front with you? - you got dibs in the back, little man. ??
- 快点 嘿... - 别管他了
- come on. hey... - don't worry about him.
待会再去抓他回来
we'll catch him later.
好吧 这孩子太兴奋了  等不及看黑板上写什么了
yeah, little man's so excited about what's on that blackboard,
这是要抢先一步去啊
he gonna race us.
大家都说我们什么了?我是指在老师休息室里
what's the line on us so far? in the teacher's lounge, i mean.
他们说你是年度创可贴
they're saying you're this year's band-aid.
- 你的感觉也是如此? - 我想做的可不仅仅如此
- is that how you feel? - i was hoping for more than that.
年度骨折夹板?
this year's splint?
嘿 Sampson女士
hey, miss sampson.
嗨 他是警察
yo, he police.
我是说 学校系统还是有益的
i mean, the school system seems benign.
我感觉就算政府不支持
and i get the sense north avenue might give us some latitude,
也会给我们一些自由空间的
if not support.
- 你真这么认为? - 听起来 你不信
- you think so? - you sound doubtful.
你能从他们的脸上看出今天是周几
you can tell the days by their faces.
最好的日子是周三
the best day is wednesday.
那天他们能远远躲开家庭
that's the farthest they get from home,
以及街区所发生的所有事
from whatever's going on in the streets.
只有这样 你才能看到微笑
you see smiles then.
周一是愤怒
monday is angry.
周二 他们的情绪卡在周一与周三之间
tuesdays, they're caught between monday and wednesday,
所以阴晴不定
so it could go either way.
周四...
thursdays...
他们感觉周末快到了
they're feeling that weekend coming.
周五 又变得很糟
friday, it's bad again.
我只能陪你到这儿了
this is where i leave you.
哦 你的班
oh, your class.
- 语文 哦? - 没错
- language arts, huh? - yes.
不管怎样 你应该单独看看
anyway, you should see it without me.
我在场时 他们的表现会大不一样
they behave differently when i'm around.
毫无疑问
no doubt.
你觉得20这个数字代表什么?
what do you think this 20 stands for?
不 它不是你被留校的次数
no, it's not the number of days you've been suspended.
也不是 你们继续浑浑噩噩过日子
it's not the number of years you'll spend
今后要在监狱度过的年数
in prison if you don't shape up.
它比一般水平低了一半
it's 50% below average.
尽管它比失败低了30%
it's 30% below failure even.
但是 事实上 它代表着
but, really, it stands for the amount of interest
你们愿意为自己的未来所做的投入
you're taking in your own future.
下面这个问题值两分
the next question is worth two points.
谁能告诉我Clarence Mitchell Jr.
who can tell me why was clarence mitchell,
- 在民权运动中起到了怎样的关键作用? - 我知道 我知道
-jr. important to the civil rights movement? - i know. i know.
我能从Shalanta的微笑中看出来
and i can tell by shalanta's smile,
她代表的蓝队要赢了
she's gonna win for the blue team.
嘿 你看到那边的那个了吗? 嘿
hey, yo, did you see that one over there? hey.
有谁是Deshawn Price吗?
anybody here deshawn price?
从来没听说过这个人
never heard of him.
那你叫什么?
and what's your name?
Berbert Brown 这是学校抓人的车 对吧?
herbert brown. this the roundup van, right?
哦 是的 找到你了 我的人 走吧
oh, yeah, here you go, my man. come on.
哦 不 不 你搞错了
oh, no, yo, no.
对吧 你看 "Howard Brown"
yeah, see, "howard brown."
那是我哥哥 他在Mchenry大街  如果你想找他的话
that's my brother. he over on mchenry street if you want him.
周五的时候我刚去过学校
i was just in school on friday,
所以十月之前 没我什么事儿 抱歉
so i'm phat till october. sorry.
- 哇 等一下  - 不用了 他说的没错
- whoa, hold up, my man. - nah, he's right.
每个孩子只要在九月上一天学
school gets a certain amount of money
十月上一天学
for each kid that shows up one day in september
- 学校就能拿到一笔钱 - 只一天?
- and one day in october. - one day?
只要做到了  政府给他们的财政拨款就不会少一分
after that, they don't lose the government money,
- 所以说 我们工作结束了 - 不 不 哥们 学生就该去上学
- so we done with it. - nah nah, man. school is school.
没错 嗯 我只是想给你上一课 兄弟
yeah, well, i'm just trying to school you, brother.
好吧
all right,
你们其中的哪个九月还需要去上学的?
which one of y'all still need your september day?
现在乖乖的
get it over with now,
今后我们也不会找你们麻烦
we won't be messing with y'all later.
你好啊 Butch
what up, butch?
从哪儿说起呢?
how do we begin?
是你把我们召集来的
you the one called the meet.
那就从尊重我的宝贵时间  把事情说清楚开始吧?
why don't we begin by you respecting my time and getting to it?
首先 我听说 也许你误以为
first of all, i heard you may be under the impression
上次Bell先生的局上  他和Mouzone兄弟跟你过不去
i was somehow involved with the late mr. bell,
是我搞的鬼
in his play against you with brother mouzone.
跟我一点关系都没有 Stringer找我
i was no way involved. stringer came at me
是他让我跟你约了 见面和谈的
to set up the parley with you.
他利用了我 就像他利用了你一样
he used me like he used y'all,
我必须把话说清楚
i feel the need to say.
说清楚了 这事儿今后不再提了
it's said then. tip out on it.
像我这样的生意人从来都不会
businessman such as myself does not believe in bad blood
与像你这样的人交恶
with a man such as yourself.
- 会让我辗转难眠的 - 肯定会的
- disturbs the sleep. - oh, i bet it do.
为了补偿 我有个提议
by way of amends, a proposition.
我知道西边有一场赌局
i know of a card game on the west side--
玩的很大 都是现金 够装一货车的
high rollers, lots of cash money, boxcar-sized.
你是想害我 Joe?
you trying to set me up, joe?
你觉得我傻吗?
you ever known me to be stupid?
我只是想跟你冰释前嫌
i'm trying to make things right here with you.
总数是多少?
how much we talking about?
至少也有几十万块在那房间
if there ain't at least a few hundred k in that room,
我真希望自己是个瞎子
i wish myself blind.
真的吗 Joe
serious, joe.
我再说一遍
i say again,
你觉得我傻吗?
have you ever known me to be a stupid man?
- 有什么条件? - 没有条件
- what are the strings? - no strings.
- 那你要分多少? - 四分之一
- what's your cut then? - quarter of the take.
我会去探消息 如果是个陷阱
i scope this and it don't look right,
我会回来找你算账的 Joe
i'm gonna come back on you now, joe.
大家都去哪儿了?
where did everybody go?
- 你们哪个是Hauk警官? - 我是 长官
- which one of you is sergeant hauk? - sir.
- 那你就是Dozerman了 - 是的 长官
- and you must be dozerman. - yes, sir.
欢迎来到重案组 我是Marimow警长
welcome to major crimes. i'm lieutenant marimow.
我听说你给市长开车不到三个月
i see you just made sergeant after driving
就当上了警司
the mayor around for less than three months.
你的车技肯定非同凡响啊
you must be a hell of a driver.
有人在吗?Greggs? Freamon?
anyone here? greggs? freamon?
Sydnor Masseyand 他们出外勤了 去大街上清毒品
sydnor and massey. and they're on the street, making rips.
我们现在就是做这个的
that's what we do here now.
我们挨个扫街 抢了毒品就跑
we get on the street and we rip and run.
这个你做得来吗 警官?
can you get with that, sergeant?
西区的风格 长官
the western district way, sir.
谢谢
thank you.
感谢大家来见我
thanks for seeing me.
我理解 大家都已经从Royce市长 和Gray议员那里听说了
i understand you've already heard from mayor royce and from councilman gray,
不过我还是要感谢大家的参与
and i'd like to thank you for being able to join in this process.
今天我没有想着要带着
i don't expect to walk out of this room today
带着不同派系部长联盟的支持离开这个房间
with an endorsement from the lnterdenominational ministerial alliance.
我没想过
i don't.
但重要的是...
but the point is...
我认为我能成为一个比现任巴尔的摩 市长更好的一任市长
i think i can be a better mayor for baltimore than the present one.
八年前我把票投给了Clarence Royce
i voted for clarence royce eight years ago.
四年后我还是把票投给了他
i voted for him four years after that.
我感觉他是个重承诺的人
i felt there was promise in the man.
但是现在我很失望
but now i'm disappointed.
我很失望 罪案以及垃圾
i'm disappointed and i'm angry
给众多街区造成了严重的伤害
at the crime and the waste
让我很愤怒
and the damage done to so many neighborhoods.
并不只是在我的辖区 也包括这里西边的
not just in my district, but here on the west side--
Pimlico Cherry Hill Edmondson Village
pimlico, cherry hill, edmondson village.
不管我到那里 人们想要的都是相同的 他们也都需要相同的东西
wherever i go, people want the same things. they need the same things,
可是他们就是得不到这些东西
but they're just not getting them.
我要改变这种现状
i'm gonna change that.
现在我不会强求你们投票给我
i'm not gonna ask for your vote now.
也许我还没能赢取到你们的投票
maybe i haven't earned it yet.
不过 我今天来这儿是为了告诉大家 一旦我当选市长
but i am here to say that when i am mayor,
我的大门是为大家敞开的 不管你支持谁
my door is open to you, regardless of who you endorse.
并且 我希望大家能够记得 今天来这儿我所说的话
and i want you to remember that i came here today to say these things.
谢谢
thank you.
议员
councilman.
谢谢你来
thank you for coming.
好吧 我要在全国通缉那个叫Tater的混球
okay, i'm gonna need an apb on a motherfucker named tater.
"尽快打电话给甜心先生"?
"call mr. sweet asap"?
让我猜猜 同性恋联盟
let me guess-- the gay and lesbian alliance.
她学的挺快的 孩子们
she's catching on, boys.
哦 你又要干嘛? 又有人偷甲烷管道?
oh, and what do you want? another methane probe?
或是什么其他根本不存在的"CSI"案件?
or some other "csl" bullshit that don't exist?
现在由你接手Braddock案子
you're the primary on the braddock case.
那个死了的证人
the dead witness.
Norris回来轮班
norris is back in the rotation.
什么?
what?
你拿到了第一个凶杀案 不错嘛
you caught your first murder. kudos.
拜托 嘿 妈的
come on, man, damn.
嘣 嘣 没错 就该这么对付打小报告的
bam bam, yeah. do that to whoever be snitching.
- 谁打小报告了? - 不知道 但是有孩子被人卖了
- who snitching? - don't know, but kids be snitching.
Rashid因为在墙上涂鸦被留校了 嘿 你们都没听说吗?
rashid got suspended for tagging walls, yo. y'all ain't heard?
你怎么知道他不是在画的时候被 抓了个正着呢?
how you know he ain't just get caught with a paint can?
因为Donnelly女士来教室把他叫出的
'cause ms. donnelly came and pulled him out of the classroom.
嘣
bam.
- 嘿 等下见啊 - 嘿 你要去运动馆?
- yo, i'll see y'all later, man. - yo, you going past the gym?
好的 好了 和平 和平
all right, man. peace, peace.
我不想再说一遍 给我遥控器
i ain't gonna tell you again. give me the remote.
你们今天学到了什么?
did y'all learn something today?
有学到东西吗?
y'all learn something today?
学了
yeah.
都学什么了?
what y'all learn?
说了 给我遥控器
i said give me the remote.
嗯
mmm-mmm.
拿来
give it.
数学是你最喜欢的 对吧? 那就先做数学
math your favorite, right? start with it.
我喜欢数学
i like math.
没错 你也很擅长
yeah, you good at it, too.
这节目都他妈看了五遍了
watched this show five damn times.
嘿 你没问题吧
hey, you good?
现在没问题了
all right now.
那么 那女孩最后...
so, it turns out the one girl...
缝了200 才把伤口缝合
200-something stitches to close her up.
看样子她还需要多次的复健  也许还需要手术
she's looking at a lot of rehab and maybe more surgery.
她现在面部的肌肉都动不了
the muscles in her face don't even move right.
同学都什么反映?
how's the class seem?
就像这事儿没发生一样
like it didn't really happen.
他们还在消化这件事 我知道虽然 表明上看不出来 但他们确实有在消化
they're still processing. i know it doesn't seem so, but they are.
Laetitia怎样?她会怎样?
what about laetitia? what happens to her?
最糟的她都已经见过了
nothing worse than she's already seen.
她可能要被送去未成年罪犯看守所
she'll probably go to a juvenile facility,
比她之前待的教养院超微差点
which is only a little worse than her group home.
她之前住过教养院?
she was in a group home?
她就是在这个系统内长大的
she grew up in the system.
周一至周五都在愤怒中度过
monday-to-friday angry.
去年 她被留校了两次 之后就被开除了
last year, she was suspended twice, and then expelled.
如果还能给你一线希望
chiquan wasn't positive though,
Chiquan没有呈阳性
if you're looking for a silver lining and all.
什么意思?
excuse me ?
她不是艾滋病毒携带者 你不用担心
she didn't have hlv, in case you were worrying.
Marcus
marcus.
孩子 你要干嘛?想要被打晕吗?
boy, what are you trying to do? you trying to get knocked out?
头低下来 孩子
drop your head, son.
左手举起来! 左手起来!把你的手举起来 妈的!
left up! get that left up! pick your hand up. damn!
妈的 那孩子有听过谁的话吗?
man, that boy listen to anyone?
好了 好了 停 停
all right, all right. time, time.
大家 都不错 不错Justin
not bad, y'all. not bad, justin.
Marcus你要集中注意力 天 多动动脑子
marcus, you got to concentrate, man. think.
行吗?
all right?
听着 我有今天晚上拳赛的票
listen, i got tickets to the fights tonight,
Pikesville兵工厂
pikesville armory.
本来我是要带Justin跟Spider去的
now, i was gonna take justin and spider,
不过Spider出不来
but spider ain't been hanging out,
而且Marcus 我知道你要照顾你妈 对吧?
and, marcus, i know you got your mother, right?
那么 Michael
so, michael,
你想去看拳击比赛吗?
you want to see the fights?
- 去吗? - 好 我去
- you going? - yeah, i'm in.
好的 好的
yeah, all right.
好的 走吧 把头套拿掉
all right. come on, get this headgear off.
他妈的 那是什么?
what the fuck is that?
纪念品
souvenir.
什么?
what?
这么做还真麻烦
trouble with doing it this way,
还他妈要毁尸灭迹
disappearing 'em and shit--
没人知道
nobody knows.
我记得当我还是孩子的时候
i remember when i was a kid,
你有张属于自己的世界地图
if you had a map of the world,
我的活动场所就在Baker
the playground over at baker and moreland
而Moreland就是我的地图中心
would be at the center of it.
然而随着我渐渐长大  我的活动区域也在逐渐扩大
and as i got older, the playground just kept on getting bigger,
已经不仅仅是附近街区了
went beyond the neighborhood.
所有一切都改变了 你知道吗?
everything changes, you know?
感觉前一分钟 你唯一想听到的是 冰激凌车的叫卖音乐
one minute the ice cream truck be the only thing you want to hear.
可是转眼间 你能听到的只剩下
next thing, them touts calling out the heroin
海洛因的叫卖声
be the only thing you can hear.
那是什么?
what's that?
需要用这个才能看懂的课本
workbook i need to use with this.
那么你是用小书帮你解决大书里面的问题?
so you read from the small one and answer questions in the big one?
是的 没什么
yeah, ain't no thing.
是的 我明白
yeah, i see that.
我明白
i see that.
好的 你看到他的手是怎么举起的了?
all right, you see how he keeping his hands up?
看他的步伐 看他们的步伐
look at his feet. look at their feet.
看他们是怎么挪动步伐的?
see how they keep their feet moving?
明白我说的了吗?
see what i'm saying?
看到他是怎么打近身战的了?
see how he stay in close?
就该这么转移他的力量
that's how you take away his power.
- 嘿 那哥们真壮 - 恩 没错
- yo, dude is cut. - yeah, man.
都是训练出来的
that's discipline.
你照顾好身体 身体也自然会照顾好你的
you take care your body, your body take care of you.
嘿 我敢打赌他的妞也很正
yo, i bet his woman is fine, man.
没错 我也相信她很正
yeah, i bet she is, too.
到Q的同花
flush to the queen.
满堂彩
full house.
好的 大家 让我看到你们的手 嘿
all right, everybody, iet me see them hands, yo.
手
hands.
嘿 大块头 后退点
hey, yo, big man, back up.
我不懂赌牌 不过
i don't know about cards, but, uh,
我想我手里的这玩意大过满堂彩了
i think these four-fives beat a full house.
嘿 银行家 给我装钱啊
hey, yo, banker, cash me out, yo.
孩子 如果你还想留脑袋在身体上 那就动作快点
boy, you want a head on that body, you best hop to.
那是我的钱
that's my money.
嘿 钱可没主人
man, money ain't got no owners,
谁能花出去那才算数
only spenders.
跟你说件别的事 我也喜欢那戒指
i tell you something else-- i like that ring, too.
孩子 你害我不停的重复自己 我有点晕
boy, you got me confused with a man repeats himself.
这事儿没完
this ain't over.
哦 你还能怎样呢 啊?
oh, that's how you carrying it, shorty, huh?
因为我要想找到你们这些人
'cause i can find your peoples
可比你们找我容易多了
a whole lot easier than they can find me.
好好带着吧
wear it in health.
毫无疑问
no doubt.
现在明白我说的了吧 Justin?
you see what i'm talking about, justin?
这才是我说的 货真价实
that's what i'm saying. that's the real deal.
继续训练 像我教你的那样 孩子  你也能那么强
you keep training, i'm telling you, boy, you can get there.
看吧 最后一击是最棒的
see, the last fight was the best.
那个波多黎各的孩子左手不错
the puerto rican boy had a good left.
是的 比赛真是激烈
yeah, shit was tight.
哦 到了 就在这 在右边
oh, this is it, right here on the right.
好的
all right.
- 那么 好的 - 好的 明天见 教练
- all right now. - all right,  i'll see you tomorrow, coach.
好的
all right.
好的 那么 你住在...
all right, now, so you live over on--
嗨 嗨 孩子 你干嘛呢
hey hey, my boy, what you doing?
- 我会送你回家 - 不了 不了 谢谢
- i'm gonna take you home. - no, no, thank you.
Michael 不是吧 搞什么
michael, come on now, serious.
不了 谢谢 我在这儿下就好
nah, no thank you. i'm good from here.